For checking if someone is greater than 60 years old,
للتحقّق من أن شخصاً يبلغ أكثر من 60 عاماً من العمر،
it's as simple as adding another age tag after the first as an else if.
فإننا ببساطة نضيف وسماً آخر للعمر بعد الوسم الأول بصيغة else-if.
And our test condition should be,
وينبغي أن تكون حالة الاختبار
if age is greater than 60.
if age &gt; 60.
This code works as an else if but would also work as just an
يعمل هذا الكود كعبارة else-if لكنه سيعمل أيضاً كعبارة if،
if since a person cannot be both less than 15 and greater than 60.
لأنه لا يمكن للمرء أن يكون أصغر من 15 عاماً وأكبر من 60 عاماً في الوقت نفسه.
Then, our last test condition is to check if someone is
ثم حالة الاختبار الأخيرة تتحقق مما إذا كان شخص ما طالباً،
a student which we can check by saying, else if isStudent.
ويمكننا التحقق من ذلك من خلال: else if (isStudent).
Then, if isStudent is true,
فإذا كانت قيمة if isStudent هي true،
we'll enter our discount block of code.
فسندخل كتلة التعليمات البرمجية للتخفيض.
Now notice that we're offering the same discount for all three of these checks.
لاحظ الآن أننا نمنح التخفيض نفسه لجميع عمليات التفقد الثلاثة هذه.
In the name of concise simple code,
لكن في سبيل الحصول على كود بسيط ومختصر،
wouldn't it be nice if we could reduce this repetition?
ألن يكون جميلاً لو استطعنا تقليل هذا التكرار؟
There is actually a way to do this by combining
هناك في الواقع طريقة للقيام بذلك من خلال دمج عمليات التفقد الثلاثة هذه